mediasynconline.com 2011-11-26

# Privacy Policy - mBLAST

Effective Date:  January 1, 2011

mBLAST, Inc. ("mBLAST") respects your privacy.  This Privacy Policy describes the types of personal information we collect on mBLAST.com, mpact.com, eventsync.com, awardsync.com, presssynconline.com and mediasynconline.com, how we use the information, with whom we share it, and the choices you can make about our use of the information.  We also describe the measures we take to protect the security of the information and how you can contact us about our privacy practices.

Click on one of the links below to jump to the listed section:

  * Information We Collect
  * How We Use The Information We Collect
  * Information We Share
  * Your Choices
  * Data Transfers
  * How We Protect Personal Information
  * Links To Other Websites
  * Updates To Our Privacy Policy
  * How To Contact Us

## Information We Collect

****The types of personal information we may collect are:

  * Contact information (such as name, postal or email address, and phone or fax number)
  * Business contact information (such as job title, department and name of organization)
  * U.S. Federal Employer ID Number, state and local ID numbers, and their foreign equivalents
  * Identification numbers or names assigned by other entities, such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, Plaxo, Dun & Bradstreet, Moody's, Amazon (Amazon Associates), Bitpipe.com, BusinessWire, ITPapers.com,MarketResearch.com, MarketWire, Pricegrabber.com, PR Newswire, ResearchAndMarkets.com or TSNN.
  * Username, password and answer to a validation question, such as mother's maiden name
  * Keywords associated with you
  * Payment information, including payment card information
  * Contact information for friends or other people you would like us to contact
  * Content you provide (such as a photograph of you or other documents)
  * Employment and biographical information
  * Information regarding your professional relationships, such as what clients you represent if you are a PR representative with a PR firm
  * Demographic information, such as gender and ethnicity or race
  * Other personal information (such as survey responses from you, and the organizational roles you might play within your organization)

When you visit our websites, we also may collect certain information by automated means, using technologies such as cookies, Web server logs, and Web beacons.  Cookies are small text files that websites send to your computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify your browser or to store information or settings in your browser.  Your browser may tell you how to be notified when you receive certain types of cookies and how to restrict or disable certain cookies.  Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to use all of the features of our websites.  In conjunction with the gathering of information through cookies, our Web servers may log information such as your operating system type, browser type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone where your device is located.  The Web server logs also may record information such as the address of the Web page that linked you to our site and the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet.  To control which Web servers collect information by automated means, we may place tags on our Web pages called "Web beacons," which are small files that link Web pages to particular Web servers and their cookies.  We use third-party web analytics services on our websites, such as those of Google Analytics.  These service providers use cookies and Web beacons to analyze use of the websites.   

## How We Use The Information We Collect

****We may use the information we obtain about you to:

  * Create and manage accounts
  * Provide, administer and communicate with you about content, surveys, products, services and promotions
  * Respond to your inquiries and requests
  * Process payments
  * Publish and distribute directories, buyer's guides, events, business information and other content through a wide variety of channels
  * Administer awards programs
  * Facilitate media credentialing and other event activities
  * Supply content to other websites and online properties
  * Permit people to find and connect with you, including for commercial or promotional purposes
  * Facilitate relationship management for you and others
  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business (including developing new products and services; managing our communications; determining the effectiveness of our advertising; analyzing our products, services and websites; facilitating the functionality of our websites; and performing accounting, auditing, billing, reconciliation and collection activities)
  * Monitor the use of and improve our interactive assets
  * Perform data analysis and market research
  * Market products and services to you and others
  * Publicly identify you as a user of our service, such as on <http://www.mblast.com/mk/who-uses-mblast/>
  * Protect against and prevent fraud, unauthorized activity, claims and other liabilities, and manage risk exposure
  * Enforce our [Terms and Conditions](http://www.mblast.com/mk/terms_and_conditions/)
  * Comply with and exercise rights under applicable legal requirements, industry standards and our policies

We also may use the information in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection.

## Information We Share

****mBLAST websites offer users innovative and powerful tools for finding and distributing information and for cultivating relationships.   We share information in conjunction with your use of these tools, to perform activities that you request and for the other purposes described above.  We share information among our expanding group of websites.  Information collected through one of our websites that is subject to this Privacy Policy may be shared with and through any of our current and future websites, including with the users and service providers of those websites, as described in our Privacy Policy.  
We may share personal information with service providers who perform services on our behalf.  We do not authorize these service providers to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements.  
On our websites, you may choose to use certain features for which we interface with other providers' services, such as Google Calendar or Facebook.  These features, which include syndication services and other information distribution services, are operated by third parties that are not affiliated with mBLAST, and we may share information with them in conjunction with the features.  These third parties may use personal information in accordance with their own privacy policies.  Where these features are offered, the relevant third parties are identified on the websites.  We strongly suggest you review the third parties' privacy policies if you use the relevant features.  
We also may disclose information about you (i) when we believe we are required to do so by law or legal process, (ii) to law enforcement authorities, or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent harm or loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity.  We also reserve the right to transfer personal information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets.  Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided to us in a manner that is consistent with our Privacy Policy.  

## Your Choices

****Our websites are designed to permit you to make choices about whether and how to share your personal information.   This functionality exists throughout our online offerings.  You can get assistance with any of our preference tools by contacting customer service at +1.770.217.0785 ext. 2 or [custservice@mblast.com](mailto:custservice@mblast.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy).  You can also contact us as specified further below to update your preferences, ask us to remove your information from our mailing lists or submit a request.  
You also can tell us not to send you marketing communications by email by clicking on the unsubscribe link within the marketing emails you receive from us or by contacting us as indicated below.  You also may opt out of receiving marketing emails from mBLAST by following the instructions [here](http://go.mblast.com/l/5922/2011-04-22/3B6L).  
In addition, your browser may tell you how to be notified when you receive certain types of cookies and how to restrict or disable certain cookies.  Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to use all of the features of our websites.

## Data Transfers

****We may transfer the personal information we collect about you to countries other than the country in which the information was originally collected.   Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information.  When we transfer your information to other countries, we will protect that information as described in this Privacy Policy.

## How We Protect Personal Information

****We maintain appropriate administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information you provide against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use.

## Links To Other Websites

****Our websites provide links to sites operated by companies not affiliated with us and not controlled by us.   Linked websites may have their own privacy policies, which we strongly suggest you review.  We are not responsible for the content of any websites that are not affiliated with us, any use of those websites, or the privacy practices of those websites.

## Updates To Our Privacy Policy

****This Privacy Policy may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal information practices.   We will post a prominent notice on our websites to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Policy and indicate at the top of the policy when it was most recently updated.  Alternatively, we may notify you by sending notice to the email address associated with you in our records.

## How To Contact Us

****If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please click[here](http://go.mblast.com/l/5922/2011-04-22/3B6L).  You also may write to:

mBLAST, Inc.  
Attn.:  Privacy  
P.O. Box 17858  
Richmond, VA 23226  
USA  
admin@mblast.com  
Telephone: +1.804.288.6864  
Fax: +1.804.288.6953
